{"name": "64E  2007-4", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. ", "choices": {"A": "-8", "B": "-6", "C": "-4", "D": "0", "E": "8"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. A consultant charges $45 for each hour she works on a consultation, plus a flat $30 consulting fee. How many hours of work are included in a $210 bill for a consultation?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "4", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "7"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. Vehicle A averages 14 miles per gallon of gasoline, and Vehicle B averages 36 miles per gallon of gasoline. At these rates, how many more gallons of gasoline does Vehicle A need than Vehicle B to make a 1,008-mile trip?", "choices": {"A": "25", "B": "28", "C": "44", "D": "50", "E": "72"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. t2 - 59t + 54 - 82t2 + 60t is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "-26t2", "B": "-26t6", "C": "-81t4 + t2 + 54", "D": "-81t2 + t + 54", "E": "-82t2 + t + 54"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. The figure below is composed of square BCDE and equilateral triangle \u25b3ABE. The length of CD is 6 inches. What is the perimeter of ABCDE, in inches?", "choices": {"A": "18", "B": "24", "C": "30", "D": "42", "E": "45"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. The expression (4z + 3)(z - 2) is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": " 4z2 - 5", "B": "4z2 - 6", "C": "4z2 - 3z - 5", "D": "4z2 - 5z - 6", "E": "4z2 + 5z -6"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. If 40% of a given number is 8, then what is 15% of the given number?", "choices": {"A": "1.2", "B": "1.8", "C": "3.0", "D": "5.0", "E": "6.5"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. The 6 consecutive integers below add up to 447.        x - 2        x - 1        x        x + 1        x + 2        x + 3What is the value of x ?", "choices": {"A": "72", "B": "73", "C": "74", "D": "75", "E": "76"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. In  the  standard  (x,y)  coordinate  plane,  point  M  with coordinates (5,4) is the midpoint of AB , and B has coordinates (7,3). What are the coordinates of A ?", "choices": {"A": "(17, 11)", "B": "(9, 2)", "C": "(6, 3.5)", "D": "(3, 5)", "E": "(-3, -5)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. Rectangle ABCD has vertices A(4,5), B(0,2), and C(6,-6). These vertices are graphed below in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane. What  are  the coordinates of vertex D ?", "choices": {"A": "(10,-3)", "B": "(9,-2)", "C": "(8,2)", "D": "(7,1)", "E": "(2,-9)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. Daisun owns 2 sportswear stores (X and Y). She stocks 3 brands of T-shirts (A, B, and C) in each store. The matrices below show the numbers of each type of T-shirt in each store and the cost for each type of T-shirt. The value of Daisun\u2019s T-shirt inventory is computed using the costs listed. What is the total value of the T-shirt inventory for Daisun\u2019s 2 stores?", "choices": {"A": "$2,200", "B": "$2,220", "C": "$4,965", "D": "$5,450", "E": "$7,350"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. Given the triangle shown below with exterior angles that measure x\u00b0, y\u00b0, and z\u00b0 as shown, what is the  sum  of x, y, and z ?", "choices": {"A": "180", "B": "231", "C": "309", "D": "360", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. Use the following information to answer question 13-15.A poll of 200 registered voters was taken before the election for mayor of Springdale. All 200 voters indicated which 1 of the 4 candidates they would vote for. The results of the poll are given in the table below.13. What percent of the voters polled chose Whitney in the poll?", "choices": {"A": "15%", "B": "20%", "C": "25%", "D": "30%", "E": "40%"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. Use the following information to answer question 13-15.A poll of 200 registered voters was taken before the election for mayor of Springdale. All 200 voters indicated which 1 of the 4 candidates they would vote for. The results of the poll are given in the table below.14. If the poll is indicative of how the 10,000 registered voters of Springdale will actually vote in the election, which of the following is the best estimate of the number of votes Lue will receive in the election?", "choices": {"A": "1,500", "B": "2,500", "C": "4,000", "D": " 5,000", "E": "8,000"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Use the following information to answer question 13-15.A poll of 200 registered voters was taken before the election for mayor of Springdale. All 200 voters indicated which 1 of the 4 candidates they would vote for. The results of the poll are given in the table below.15. If the information in the table were converted into a circle graph (pie chart), then the central angle of the sector for Gomez would measure how many degrees?", "choices": {"A": " 54\u00b0", "B": " 72\u00b0", "C": " 90\u00b0", "D": " 108\u00b0", "E": " 144\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. In square ABCE shown below, D is the midpoint of CE . Which of the following is the ratio of the area of \u25b3ADE to the area of \u25b3ADB ?", "choices": {"A": "1:1", "B": "1:2", "C": "1:3", "D": "1:4", "E": "1:8"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. Which of the following is the slope of a line parallel to the line  in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": "-4", "B": "", "C": "2", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. Janelle cut a board 30 feet long into 2 pieces. The ratio of the lengths of the 2 pieces is 2:3. What is the length, to the nearest foot, of the shorter piece?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "6", "C": "12", "D": "15", "E": "18"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. What is the smallest integer greater than ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "7", "C": "8", "D": "10", "E": "30"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. Sergio plans to paint the 4 walls of his room with 1 coat of paint. The walls are rectangular, and, according to his measurements, each wall is 10 feet by 15 feet. He will not need to paint the single 3-foot-by-5-foot rectangular window in his room and the -foot-by-7-foot rectangular door. Sergio knows that each gallon of paint covers between 300 and 350 square feet. If only 1-gallon cans of paint are available, which of the following is the minimum number of cans of paint Sergio needs to buy to paint his walls?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "4", "E": "5"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. What values of x are solutions for x2 + 2x = 8?", "choices": {"A": "-4 and 2", "B": "-2 and 0", "C": "-2 and 4", "D": "0 and 2", "E": "6 and 8"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. For all a &gt; 1, the expression equals:", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "-a2", "C": "a2", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. If point M has a nonzero x-coordinate and a nonzero y-coordinate and the coordinates have opposite signs, then  point  M  must  be  located  in   which of  the  4 quadrants labeled below?", "choices": {"A": "I only", "B": "III only", "C": "I or III only", "D": "I or IV only", "E": "II or IV only"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. The fixed costs of manufacturing basketballs in a factory are $1,400.00 per day. The variable costs are $5.25 per basketball. Which of the following expressions can be used to model the cost of manufacturing b basketballs in  1 day?", "choices": {"A": "$1,405.25b", "B": "$5.25b - $1,400.00", "C": "$1,400.00b + $5.25", "D": "$1,400.00 - $5.25b", "E": "$1,400.00 + $5.25b"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. In the figure below, where \u25b3ABC ~ \u25b3KLM, lengths given are in centimeters. What is the perimeter, in centimeters, of \u25b3ABC ?(Note: The symbol ~ means \u201cis similar to.\u201d)", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "14", "C": "", "D": "35", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. If  is true, the a = ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "", "C": "7", "D": "21", "E": "49"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. A hot-air balloon 70 meters above the ground is falling at a constant rate of 6 meters per second while another hot-air balloon 10 meters above the ground is rising at  a constant rate of 15 meters per second. To the nearest tenth of  a  second, after how  many seconds will the 2 balloons be the same height above the ground?", "choices": {"A": "8.9", "B": "6.7", "C": "2.9", "D": "0.4", "E": "0.2"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. A hiking group will go from a certain town to a certain village by van on 1 of 4 roads, from the village to a waterfall by riding bicycles on 1 of 2 bicycle paths, and then from the waterfall to their campsite by hiking on 1 of 6 trails. How many routes are possible for the hiking group to go from the town to the village to the waterfall to their campsite?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "12", "C": "24", "D": "48", "E": "220"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Cube A has an edge length of 2 inches. Cube B has an edge length double that of Cube A. What is the volume, in cubic inches, of Cube B ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "8", "C": "16", "D": "32", "E": "64"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. A formula used to compute the current value of a savings account is A = P(1 + r)n, where A is the current value; P is the amount deposited; r is the rate of interest for 1 compounding period, expressed as a decimal; and n is the number of compounding periods. Which of the following is closest to the value of a savings account after 5 years if $10,000 is deposited at 4% annual interest compounded yearly?", "choices": {"A": "$10,400", "B": "$12,167", "C": "$42,000", "D": "$52,000", "E": "$53,782"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. A right circular cylinder is shown in the figure below, with dimensions given in centimeters. What is the total surface area of this cylinder, in square centimeters?(Note: The total surface area of a cylinder is given by 2\u03c0r2 + 2\u03c0rh where r is the radius and h is the height.)", "choices": {"A": "300\u03c0", "B": "400\u03c0", "C": "500\u03c0", "D": "600\u03c0", "E": "1,600\u03c0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Given f(x) = 4x + 1 and g(x) = x2 - 2, which of the following is an expression for f(g(x)) ?", "choices": {"A": "-x2 + 4x + 1", "B": "x2 + 4x - 1", "C": "4x2 - 7", "D": "4x2 - 1", "E": "16x2 + 8x - 1"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. The table below shows the total number of goals scored in each of 43 soccer matches in a regional tournament. What is the average number of goals scored per match, to the nearest 0.1 goal?", "choices": {"A": "1.0", "B": "2.8", "C": "3.0", "D": "6.1", "E": "17.1"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Lines a, b, c, and d are shown below and a \u01c1 b. Which  of the following is the set of all angles that must be supplementary to \u2220x ?", "choices": {"A": " {1, 2}", "B": "{1, 2, 5, 6}", "C": "{1, 2, 9, 10}", "D": "{1, 2, 5, 6, 9, 10}", "E": "{1, 2, 5, 6, 9, 10, 13, 14}"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. (3x3)3 is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "x", "B": "9x6", "C": "9x9", "D": "27x6", "E": "27x9"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Which of the following is equivalent to the inequality 4x - 8 &gt; 8x + 16 ?", "choices": {"A": "x &lt; -6", "B": "x &gt; -6", "C": "x &lt; -2", "D": "x &gt; 2", "E": "x &lt; 6"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. As shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, P(6,6) lies on  the circle with center (2,3) and radius  5 coordinate units. What are the coordinates of the image of P after the circle is rotated 90\u00b0 clockwise () about the center of the circle?", "choices": {"A": "\uff082, 3\uff09", "B": "(3, 2)", "C": "(5, -1)", "D": "(6, 0)", "E": "(7, 3)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. For right triangle \u25b3KLM below, what is sin\u2220M ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. In the figure below, B lies on AC , BD bisects \u2220ABE, and BE bisects \u2220CBD. What is the measure of \u2220DBE ?", "choices": {"A": "90\u00b0", "B": "60\u00b0", "C": "45\u00b0", "D": "30\u00b0", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. If there are 8 \u00d7 1012 hydrogen molecules in a volume of 4 \u00d7 104 cubic centimeters, what is the  average number of hydrogen molecules per cubic centimeter?", "choices": {"A": "5 \u00d7 10-9", "B": "2 \u00d7 103", "C": "2 \u00d7 108", "D": "32 \u00d7 1016", "E": "32 \u00d7 1048"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. In the figure below, a radar screen shows 2 ships. Ship A is located at a distance of 20 nautical miles and bearing 170\u00b0, and Ship B is located at a  distance of  30 nautical miles and bearing 300\u00b0. Which of the following is an expression for  the  straight-line distance, in nautical miles, between the 2 ships?(Note: For \u25b3ABC with side of length a opposite \u2220A, side of length b opposite \u2220B, and side of length c opposite \u2220C,    the     law     of     cosines     states c2 = a2 + b2 - 2ab cos \u2220C.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. What rational number is halfway between  and  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. In isosceles trapezoid ABCD, AB is parallel to DC, \u2220BDC measures 25\u00b0, and \u2220BCA measures 35\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220DBC ?", "choices": {"A": "85\u00b0", "B": "95\u00b0", "C": "105\u00b0", "D": "115\u00b0", "E": "125\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. In the figure below, the area of  the  larger square is 50 square centimeters and the area of the smaller square is 18 square centimeters. What  is x, in centimeters?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "16", "E": "32"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. Which of the following is a rational number?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. If a &lt; b, then is equivalent to which of the following?", "choices": {"A": "a + b", "B": "-(a + b)", "C": "", "D": "a - b", "E": "-(a - b)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. Tom  has taken 5  of the 8  equally weighted tests in  his U.S. History class this semester, and he has an average score of exactly 78.0 points. How many points does he need to earn on the 6th test to bring his average score up to exactly 80.0 points?", "choices": {"A": "90", "B": "88", "C": "82", "D": "80", "E": "79"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. In the complex plane, the horizontal axis is called the real axis and the vertical axis is called the imaginary axis. The complex number a + bi graphed in the complex plane is comparable to the point (a,b) graphed in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane. The modulus of the complex number a + bi is given by . Which of the complex numbers z1, z2, z3, z4, and z5 below has the greatest modulus?", "choices": {"A": "z1", "B": "z2", "C": "z3", "D": "z4", "E": "z5"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. In the real numbers, what is the solution of the equation 82x + 1 = 41 - x ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "0", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. The graph of the trigonometric function y = 2 cos(x) is shown below.The function is:", "choices": {"A": "even (that is, f (x) = f (-x) for all x).", "B": "odd (that is, f (-x) = -f (x) for all x).", "C": "neither even nor odd.", "D": "the inverse of a cotangent function.", "E": "undefined at x = \u03c0."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. An integer from 100 through 999, inclusive, is to be chosen at random. What is the probability that the number chosen will have 0 as at least 1 digit?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. In the figure below, line q in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane has equation -2x + y = 1 and intersects line r, which is distinct from line q, at a point on the x-axis. The angles, \u2220a and \u2220b, formed by these lines and the x-axis are congruent. What is the slope of line r ?", "choices": {"A": "-2", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "2", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. In the right triangle below, 0 &lt; b &lt; a. One  of  the angle measures in the triangle is tan-1(). What is cos [ tan-1() ] ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. Use the following information to answer question 54-56.The radio signal from the transmitter site of radio station WGGW can be received only within a radius of 52 miles in all directions from the transmitter site. A map of the region of coverage of the radio signal is shown below in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, with the transmitter site at the origin and 1 coordinate unit representing 1 mile.54. Which of the following is closest to the area, in square miles, of the region of coverage of the radio signal?", "choices": {"A": "2,120", "B": "2,700", "C": "4,250", "D": "8,500", "E": "16,990"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. Use the following information to answer question 54-56.The radio signal from the transmitter site of radio station WGGW can be received only within a radius of 52 miles in all directions from the transmitter site. A map of the region of coverage of the radio signal is shown below in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, with the transmitter site at the origin and 1 coordinate unit representing 1 mile.55. Which of the following is an equation of the circle shown on the map?", "choices": {"A": "x + y =52", "B": "(x + y)2 =52", "C": "(x + y)2 =522", "D": "x2 + y2 =52", "E": "x2 + y2 =522"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. Use the following information to answer question 54-56.The radio signal from the transmitter site of radio station WGGW can be received only within a radius of 52 miles in all directions from the transmitter site. A map of the region of coverage of the radio signal is shown below in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, with the transmitter site at the origin and 1 coordinate unit representing 1 mile.56. The transmitter site of radio station WGGW and the transmitter site of another radio station, WGWB,  are on the same highway 100 miles apart. The radio signal from the transmitter site of WGWB can be received only within a radius of 60 miles in all directions from the WGWB transmitter site. For how many miles along the highway can the radio signals of both stations be received?(Note: Assume the highway is straight.)", "choices": {"A": " 8", "B": "12", "C": " 40", "D": "44", "E": "48"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. The graphs of the equations y = x - 1 and y = (x - 1)4 are shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below. What real values of x, if any,  satisfy the inequality   (x - 1)4 &lt; (x - 1) ?", "choices": {"A": "No real values", "B": "x &lt; 0 and x &gt; 1", "C": "x &lt; 0 and x &gt; 2", "D": "0 &lt; x &lt; 1", "E": "1 &lt; x &lt; 2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. For every positive 2-digit number, x, with tens digit t and units digit u, let y be the 2-digit number formed by reversing the digits of x. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to x - y ?", "choices": {"A": "9(t - u)", "B": "9(u - t)", "C": "9t - u", "D": "9u - t", "E": "0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. In the figure below, the vertices of \u25b3ABC have (x, y) coordinates (4,5), (5,3), and (1,3), respectively. What  is the area of \u25b3ABC ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "8", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. The sum of an infinite geometric series with first term a and common ratio r &lt; 1 is given by . The sum of a given infinite geometric series is 200, and the common ratio is 0.15. What is the second term of this series?", "choices": {"A": "25.5", "B": "30", "C": "169.85", "D": "170", "E": "199.85"}, "correct": "A"}]}